rm.com 2017-11-15

# Privacy Policy - RM Education

RM has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to the privacy of our customers, candidates and visitors to our site. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website, www.rm.com our ecommerce pages on shops.rm.com, our group corporate pages on rmplc.com, and our support and account pages - support.rm.com and account.rm.com respectively. See the information at the bottom of this policy for information specific to careers.rm.com. 

##### Cookies and IP addresses

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our website. Your IP address is also used to gather broad demographic information.   
Your IP address is also used to gather broad demographic information.

Our websites use cookies, which are small text files on your computer. A cookie contains identifying information. The cookie is used to make the link between you and the information you have provided to the website. This allows us to help identify your computer so we can tailor your user experience, remember where you are in the order process and your shopping basket to be kept separate from other users. It also enables us to automatically complete some of the forms when you subsequently use them. The creation of a cookie on your computer does not give the website any access to other information such as your email address. You can disable any cookies already stored on your computer, but these may stop our website from functioning properly. 

The European Union Directive on Privacy and Electronic Communications (the "Directive"), which came into force on 31st July 2002, recognises that cookies are a "legitimate and useful tool" for many activities, including verifying the identity of web site users. The Directive makes it compulsory for websites to inform users if cookies are being used, and to provide some information on how cookies are used.

Read more about our use of cookies.

##### How we may use your personal information

We (or third-party data processors acting on our behalf) may collect, store, and use your personal information for the following purposes:

  * to make this website available to you and to provide you with content which is tailored to your individual tastes;
  * to provide you with services that you request and to respond to any enquiries you submit through the website;
  * monitor, develop and improve the services and/or your experience; and
  * to provide you with electronic marketing information. 

##### Contact information

Our site's registration form requires you to provide us with some contact information (e.g. name and email address). We sometimes use this contact information from the registration form to send you information about our company and our products and services by phone, email, fax etc. This contact information is also used to contact you when necessary. If at any time you wish to stop receiving information from RM please contact us and we will update our records accordingly.

This site contains links to other sites. RM is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.

Our site uses a form to help us manage requests. We collect contact information (like email addresses). Contact information is used to respond to enquiries, or get in touch with you when necessary.

Our online surveys ask for contact information (like email addresses). We use contact information from our surveys to send information about our company.

We run competitions on our site in which we ask for contact information (like email addresses). We use contact information from competitions to send information about our company. Contact information is also used to contact you when necessary. Any other information is shared only within the RM Group of companies or selected third parties.

##### Remarketing opt-out

Sometimes RM uses 'remarketing' or 'similar audiences' to advertise online. This is the use of a specific cookie to inform Google of the pages visited by a certain visitor/device. Third-party vendors, including Google, use these cookies to serve ads based on someone's past visits to websites including www.rm.com - the large Google Display Network of affiliate sites mean that these targeted advertisements could appear on a number of websites and applications.

To find out more or to opt out of Google Ad Personalisation please visit <https://adssettings.google.com/u/0/authenticated>

##### Public forums

This site may include chat rooms, forums, message boards, and news groups. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

##### Security

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. All instances of unauthorised attempted access to our site are logged and investigated. Where necessary RM will inform law enforcement agencies or other relevant organisations regarding misconduct.

##### Email

At RM we respect the privacy of email accounts and we store your email addresses just as securely as other information on our websites. However, we may use email to keep you up to date with news about products, services and offers that we think may be of interest to you. If you do not want to be kept informed in this way by email, please let us know. You can do this by ticking the relevant box where your email address is stored when you register or by choosing the unsubscribe option within the email.

##### Where we store your personal data

Your personal information is stored on a secure server hosted by an RM approved contractor. The server resides in the United Kingdom.

RM is a global organisation, therefore, your data may be transferred to any of our operating businesses throughout the world.

Your personal data may be processed by staff operating outside the European Economic Area ("EEA") who work for us (employed by our wholly owned subsidiary, RM Education Solutions India Pvt) or for one of our suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal information, you agree to RM transferring, storing and processing your personal information outside the EEA.

If you do not agree to this procedure you should not use our services.

##### Choice/opt-out

Our site provides you with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us at the point where we request contact information from you. Additionally, each time you receive electronic marketing information from us, you have the option to decline to receive further marketing information from us. 

To prevent you receiving such communications from RM in the future, you can:

  1. send your question using contact us or 
  2. send a letter clearly identifying yourself and asking that we remove you from our contact lists; or 
  3. tick on the opt-out link in the emails (if relevant) and follow the instructions. 

Letters should be sent to:

Privacy - RM Marketing  
140 Eastern Avenue  
Milton Park  
Abingdon, Oxfordshire  
OX14 4SB  
United Kingdom

##### Correct/update

To change or modify information previously provided, you can:

  1. send your request using contact us and provide the correct information; or
  2. send a letter clearly identifying yourself and asking that we correct or update our database.

Letters should be sent to:

Privacy - RM Marketing  
140 Eastern Avenue  
Milton Park  
Abingdon, Oxfordshire  
OX14 4SB  
United Kingdom

##### Contacting the web site

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, you can:

  1. send your question using contact us; or
  2. send your question in a letter.

Letters should be sent to:

RM Marketing  
140 Eastern Avenue  
Milton Park  
Abingdon, Oxfordshire  
OX14 4SB  
United Kingdom  
Telephone: +44 (0) 8450 700300  
Fax: +44 (0) 8450 700400  
[webmaster@rm.com  
](mailto:webmaster@rm.com)

In this privacy statement, all references to

  * "RM" means RM Education Ltd.
  * "RM Group" means the RM plc Group of companies which includes RM and the other subsidiary undertakings of RM plc. 

## Privacy policy for careers.rm.com

We understand that when searching for employment a large amount of personal and highly confidential data is disclosed and we take our responsibility to protect this very seriously. This policy sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or you provide to us, will be processed by us.

##### Information we may collect

We generally collect information contained in your CV such as name, address, home phone number, work phone number, mobile phone number(s), facsimile numbers, email addresses and general contact information to facilitate RM to be able to readily communicate with you. We also collect additional personal information such as your CV.

We collect and may disclose statistical information gathered as a whole (e.g. total number of applicants and applicant origin) for internal reporting purposes. However, we never disclose information that identifies any individual for such purposes. We do not knowingly solicit information from children and we do not knowingly market our services to children.

If you opt to provide date of birth, sex, marital status or nationality information, this information is gathered for diversity monitoring and reporting only and will not be used in the recruitment and selection process.

##### How we may use this Information

RM gathers the personal information required for you to be considered for job vacancies within RM and to conduct research relating to our recruitment activities. Generally, the information gathered from you is used to assist you to search for RM job vacancies, apply for RM job vacancies and to be processed for each job application you submit. As such, it may require us to release your personal information with your consent to RM hiring managers, administrators and third party contractors. These RM hiring managers, administrators and third party contractors may be in the UK or in other parts of the world including outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). By registering with RM, you agree that your information may be shared with RM hiring managers, administrators and third party contractors for the purpose of supporting you to find suitable RM job vacancies, applying for RM job vacancies, supporting our research relating to our recruitment activities and processing you for each job application you submit and you consent to the transfer of your information outside the EEA. 

We may also use, disclose and communicate your personal information for compliance with any legal obligation to which we may be subject.

RM uses all reasonable means to ensure that third party sources use your personal information only for the purposes for which it was provided and in adherence to the RM Privacy Policy. However, RM is not responsible for any improper use of your personal information that is beyond our reasonable control.

We do not disclose your information to anyone except as described above, including personal information, CV information, email addresses, information about your visits our sites, etc.

##### Third party links

Our careers site may, from time to time, contain links to other sites. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

##### Where we store your personal data

Your personal information is stored on a secure server hosted by an RM approved contractor. The server resides in the EEA. RM is a global organisation, therefore, your data may be transferred to any of our operating businesses throughout the world with your consent, for the purpose of being considered for any RM job vacancy you apply for, or for being matched to specific RM job vacancies and being contacted by a RM hiring manager, administrator or third party contractor to discuss your interest and suitability.

By submitting your personal information, you agree to RM transferring, storing and processing your personal information outside the EEA. In particular, you agree to our wholly owned subsidiary, RM Education Solutions India Pvt, processing your data outside the EEA.

##### How is your personal information secured and protected?

We use commercially reasonable measures necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk.

Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access to the same.

##### Access to information

The Data Protection Act (“Act”) gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 towards our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

##### Changes to our privacy policy

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.
